by the way tomorrow you're gonna get
another reading okay
it's called Edom review and Edom you
know it's a picture that's supposed to
remind you of an idea from the long room
and I did something like a hundred and
almost 200 of them already
I prepared about 200 of them for the
long room we covered in the last eight
years okay
and I'm not finished but uh and then we
were supposed to go through them in
Thailand there's something and I got too
busy which was very unusual and I only
covered
I think Jamie told me 78 of them or
something so tomorrow you're gonna get
another reading which is you know just
color pictures and you can test yourself
to see if you remember what they mean
okay and I'll explain them alright and
we're starting it I think 78 or 79 and
these are review of the eight years of
long room okay and the idea is that if
you become an ACI teacher you can choose
to specialize like if you go to law
school you can choose to be a I don't
know criminal lawyer or business lawyer
or intellectual property lawyer okay
so you kind of have a choice in ACI
teacher training you got the basic
you're gonna get a basic ACI teacher
training that you can teach the ACI
course one for example right then you
can specialize you can add a specialty
and we're thinking like
a meditation specialized er so some
people instead of teaching the courses
they would like to teach the meditations
or maybe you get invited to some company
and they want you to teach meditation
but they don't care about the courses so
everybody should have the courses okay
that's a basic law school and then you
can add a specialty so you can be a long
room expert okay
meditation for us is gonna be Lamia
meditations from those items so tomorrow
we'll start going to I don't know it's
like 200 meditations okay from the last
eight years and you don't have to learn
them but if you want to you can be a
specialty lawyer who just does I don't
know
car accidents something like that okay
all right so there'll be that kind of
specialty they'll also be a specialty
called retreat master okay if you're
attracted to doing long retreats which
some people are and some people are not
okay so if you're the kind of person who
wants to help people through long
retreats say one week to three years
then you can specialize you could be a
ACI teacher who specializes in long
retreats okay and then we're thinking
there could be subject specialties like
Kamala Sheila okay so Kamala Sheila we
did five years of kamila Sheila it's the
greatest commentary to the diamond
cutter Sutra from ancient times and it
has a full set of items and you could
learn those and you could have a Camilla
Sheila master's degree understand so
you're having a bachelor's degree this
week right
and then you could do a specialty in
Camilla Sheila so if people are
interested in diamond cutter Sutra you
could be that person who has a master's
in Camilla Sheila with your BA in the
ACI courses understand and we're gonna
design a master's course in the gardener
okay and I started it last November here
and October and it will take five years
to finish okay but if you want to
specialize in the gardener
then try to come every fall to Diamond
Mountain we're going through some
coppice commentary to the gardener's
most famous book wisdom and it's
incredible it's it's incredible it's
really really good
okay so you don't have to do any of
those master's degrees you can just have
a bachelor degree and I don't mind and
you can teach a CI if you're certified
but if you want to specialize you can
add meditation master retreat master
lamrim master it's kind of meditation
master or commercial a master or
Nagarjuna master cool man okay I
understand I just was supposed to stall
because they broke some equipment did I
do it hello hi let's get going okay
we're gonna do normal new material
[Music]
let's see you can look up baam space pa
ba M space PA and we'll hit the right
place bum ba la Bamba got it
baam space PA it's unique
it won't it'll occur once in this text I
predict be a.m. space PA oh you never
saw it before
me neither yeah that's it good okay here
we go he's talking about the first of
the six primary negative emotions which
was desire okay
lower school see now that you had the
whole outline of the ACI training the
five topics the fourth and a half
schools now you can appreciate how much
Buddha taught on different levels so he
gave one teaching but it's it has many
different levels many different people
will see many different teachings in the
same words okay so the lower school way
of thinking about the study of the
desire is don't want anything okay don't
don't buy new cars don't wear nice
clothes you know live in a cave and
that's okay there's a place for that
especially if you're distracted by
material things you know if you're the
kind of personality who gets caught up
you know and making money and then
suddenly you die okay and you lose
everything okay so that that's okay that
kind of teaching is okay but on a higher
level
what we really want to do is learn to
share so desire becomes the opposite of
sharing okay it's okay to like chocolate
chip cookies but it's if you like them
don't refuse to share them because you
won't get more you see that's all so
desire becomes a kind of stupidity and
not a kind of emotion you see they're
smart desire and their stupid desire
okay
smart desire is the geshe-la shares his
cookies because geshe-la wants more
cookies okay and it's not a bad thing
okay it's it's actually you can never
get anything at all in your whole life
not one piece of tissue paper unless you
share with other people so it's not bad
okay intelligent desire okay it's not
desire got it because it makes the world
happy alright okay alright now if we
take desire to be attachment to your
body for example okay there are
traditional lower school antidotes okay
traditional meditations and he's gonna
talk about one we're gonna talk about
one this morning and it's called me
duper Goomba say me duper come back or
you can say kangaroo it sounds like
kangaroo in Australia kangaroo teens in
okay me duper Goomba means mister human
dictionary this stupa means beautiful
some meat duper gumbo yeah
ugly meditation meditation on ugliness
okay and a famous example of it is King
ruthenians in which is I'm not gonna he
doesn't teach it here yeah yeah he
doesn't teach it here but you can do it
here if you want
it's an old abhidharma meditation where
you you meditate that there's a little
what he call you get
what's that disease where you lose your
legs and no gangrene yeah so a little
tiny spot of green here and then it
starts to spread it's rotting your skin
is rotting and then it starts to spread
and you can see the bone of your skull
and then it starts to spread you're on
your meditation seat and you do your
whole skull and then your whole skull is
no skin and no flush and then you move
it down to your body until your whole
body is like rotten then you do the
meditation scene and it gets old and all
the threads break and the stuff falls
down and then you start doing the the
building and it gets old and you know
one day this building will fall down
right we originally made all the
buildings out of Adobe which is the
earth we made our own bricks this this
building is Adobe and our dream was that
it would melt back into the earth you
know when we're all gone
and if diamond mountain ever ends not as
long as to forget that's in charge but
the Adobe will actually melt there won't
be anything here okay we just melted the
cat's old house she made a house out of
Adobe and it melted it's gone okay so in
the meditation it's like nuclear bomb
you know the house this house gets all
the building falls down then you go to
the highway and all the cars break and
the highway falls apart then you go to
Tucson
one day Tucson will be empty we don't
know when but one day it will be empty
probably there's no water enough water
for Tucson and people just go away
it'll be like Chernobyl right and you
know it'll just be empty so you do this
meditation you go to the ocean you reach
the ocean
California and New York then you dry up
the ocean all the fish are dead the
ocean is gone you see so that's a
postive lesson your desire that's a
kangaroo thing engine that's called
skeleton meditation he has another one
here all right so we're gonna go through
this one here we go
Dean nimble Nimbo means how can you fix
your desire for things or people or your
body me duper Goomba you can do the
meditation called me duper which means
how would you say distasteful or growth
or okay then here means practice BST BST
which is not BRT which means to practice
they allow me do what does me duper mean
number Mara okay what smart ball red and
it means you peel the skin off so like
if you can't stop looking at someone's
wife or husband and you have a trouble
you think you're gonna do something bad
with them just peel the skin off with
your meditation and see who they really
are and it looks like steak you know
we're all steak you know color inch down
okay and it's disgusting disgusting
meditation let's call it disgusting
meditation me dupa and you peel the skin
off with your meditation okay your
meditation is so strong the next time
you see this woman or man who's married
already to somebody else you're gonna go
ear you know so by the way it's a lower
school right it's a lower school it
might not work that's a definition of
lower school it might not work it might
work
you might not work a better meditation
to do is higher highest school
Prasanna and say look suppose you
do steal this man or woman from their
husband or their wife their karma that
is you will always lose your partners
for the rest of your life and I don't
want that I just don't want that if I
want if I steal someone's wife I want to
keep on but if you steal someone's life
you can't keep them
so it's stupid okay so that's a better
method than peeling the skin but
sometimes this will work okay
it's like aspirin okay sometimes this
meditation you peel their skin on it's
called number Marwa it's called red
steak okay second one number tawa sooner
or later this person will die and their
arm will get disconnected from the rest
they used to have a punishment in in
England draw and quarter to connect
chains to your arms and legs connected
to four horses and hit the horses and it
tears the person into four parts you
know and they used to hang the parts
around four different cities to show you
know the punishment and and they would
leave it up for for a year something
this person's like okay and it's gross
right it's like disgusting to think you
it's called quartering person and you
rip them into four parts and then you
hang the part up for like a year in the
town as a sign to all the other people
you see but we're all gonna be quartered
okay we're all gonna be there you know
this woman you're trying to steal from
her husband or this husband you're
trying to steal from his wife it's gonna
get cornered also it's just meat okay
all right so that will help you not have
desire it only works sometimes seeds
works always okay seeds works always
this works sometimes this is lower
circle okay next one number Baumbach we
don't have that word word doesn't know
that word I don't know this morning but
I looked it up and it means they were
also wrong their skin
meet their nose they're beautiful nose
they're delicious lips they're beautiful
ears will also rot in a box somewhere
okay and you you visualize you go Maya I
don't know my dad used to say if you
fall in love he I'm like 18 years old he
says if you fall in love with a girl
check out her mother first you know
because that's what's gonna happen you
know and then anyway okay so number
pamba means your skin will rot away in
the box after you die okay so if you
have attachment to someone else's
partner you could think about their
finger rotting for example okay all
right
Wukong through conga to say here do
really means conceive of them in a
certain way and it's one of the five
heaps right
and it means bounce okay
after the routing is finished I think
about my mom sometimes I think all this
left of her is bones in a box you see if
I could dig up her box
it's just bones now you know and it
would look like anybody else's bones I
wouldn't be able to see if it's my mom
or not you see and this woman you want
to you know have an affair with is just
the bones in the end she's bones okay
and there were all bones so it's not
that sexy
unless it's Halloween or something I
don't know okay all right okay
mmm by the way there's a more formal
teaching on this meditation you want to
go deeper okay I knew you'd say yes and
I went and got it for you
it's from the progeny of paramita
scriptures in the Gashi course which
means yeah lower middle way but they
have a nice presentation and there's
actually nine steps
- this adultery meditation okay there's
actually nine steps he just mentioned a
few of them so when they teach the nine
parts of disgusting meditation they
actually list what it's an antidote for
okay so there's nine parts of the
meditation and there's nine things it's
fixing it fixes nine problems okay so
I'm teaching you the deeper one okay
that's why this laundry room is so slow
it's gonna take like 20 years we're
about halfway through okay here's here's
the nine ready okay
number one if you're attracted to this
person's you know body shape oh look at
her breasts look at her hips you know
look at his muscles you know then the
specific disgusting meditation is
rotting okay think of those muscles of
rotting think of those breasts rotting
think of those hips rotting okay got it
so if you have a breast or bicep problem
with someone else's wife or husband do a
rotting meditate see that biceps are
rotting after they die or the breasts
rotting okay got it cool happy
disgusting well that's in there the
meditation okay number two if you have a
sexual attraction towards the other
person oh I'd like to have sex with this
person you know who's already married
okay
yeah
imagine the maggots drilling into that
beautiful thing that you want to drill
into understand okay like you want
something like this then think about the
maggot then the worms are gonna drill
into this person
okay okay got it you're not the only one
who wants to drill into this person
maggot is the fly egg opens and it's a
small white worm and they eat they eat
meat or they eat things worm okay two
kinds of worm I mean one you dig in the
earth and you find a worm okay they will
also eat you but before they get to eat
you the fly worm will eat you because
flies lay eggs everywhere they go okay
you have to fly eggs on you now okay and
they will eat you if you die today okay
they will be the they will drill you you
already have the driller on your skin
you have already okay
and they will you will be their meat
okay you will be their dinner you could
be their dinner today
we don't know okay got it are you
disgusted yet okay number three if you
are attracted to this person's bodily
smell
Farren note pheromone pheromone friend
ohm I don't like if you get near them
and you're like mmm you know I'm
attracted to you
they say menstrual blood has pheromones
in it if a woman is menstruating and a
man's nearby they're like animals
they're like you know there's some
subconscious attraction to the smell of
another human being and if you have this
problem then imagine the the smell of
the rotten water and pus that comes out
of their body okay when you read about
like earthquakes or tornadoes and mass
murders they they often mentioned the
smell of a human body deteriorating it's
the worst smell in the world I haven't
smelled it I guess that a nurse at a
funeral home I've smelled it but it's
supposed to be like the worst smell in
the world you know I had a meeting
George Soros the richest men one of the
richest people in the world
with his daughter and she was gonna
support one of our projects and then I
was supposed to go to New York and that
night one of our congregation died so I
was a monk in the temple and one of our
members died and I was really freaked
out because I'm here's this lady who can
support ACIP for a thousand years and
but I'm supposed to go to the funeral
home to take care of this guy so I I
cancelled and I went to the funeral home
and he's a good friend and he's out on
the table metal table and when I walked
in and they keep the room very cold
because they don't want the smell and I
walk in and there he is you know and
he's naked on this metal table I'm like
don't you feel cold and he's like and
then there's they take your blood out
they pump your blood out and they
replace it with kind of alcohol and they
were pumping his blood out and this is
how they keep you for 3-4 days without
smelling so your family can come see you
okay and they they have to take your
blood out quickly before it gets hard
and it was unbelievable you know I
freaked out I'm supposed to do his Bardo
prayers so I sat there for two three
hours and did his Bardo purse but it was
really hard okay okay so if you're
attracted to a person's body fragrance
then or their perfume or their after
shape then think about how they're gonna
smell two days after they die okay all
right number four if the person you're
attracted to is really good at wearing
jewelry like nice earrings and nice
necklace or nice bracelets or okay then
you peel their skin off okay that's when
you do the red one red steak meditation
okay specifically in the ancient text if
you're attracted to
there's fashion style you know oh they
dress so cool or they wear such cool
things then peel the skin off and check
out this ornament you know red state
okay got it
disgusting yes it's supposed to be
alright number five if you're attracted
to their complexion you know some women
a very pale very beautiful complexion
mexican ladies very beautiful golden
color of their body and you know if
you're attracted to a person's color
okay skin color then do the green thing
okay what do you call it mold
you know this green what do you call it
fungus it the body when it rots it turns
green the skin turns green little green
things girl like what do you call it
anyway you understand more it molds the
skin moles and it becomes green okay we
call in Tibet we can't look look if you
get gangrene for example the green in
gangrene means your skin turns green and
it starts to follow okay okay so if
you're attracted to their color change
it to green like an old banana okay
something like that
alright shag a brother chopping em their
number City douchey if you're attracted
to their muscles or I don't know zsakeba
means girth it means that big muscles or
how do you say that bill yeah good you
know
in in India still if you're fat it's
beautiful okay it's like Europe in the
500 years ago it means you have money it
means you're not hungry
okay so anyone who was big was
considered more attractive okay now in
America it's the opposite you have to be
too skinny unhealthy skinny and it will
change tenure you know it changes it
comes and goes sometimes skinny is
popular sometimes fat is popular okay so
anyway in those days big was popular and
they said if you are attracted to the
big then just think about them being
eaten by bugs and mice and after they
die okay your body gets eaten by
cockroaches and okay things like that
okay that's number six are you disgusted
yes okay
that's who we are by the way it takes a
lot of imagination to be attracted to
someone you know it takes a lot of
fooling yourself to not notice they are
dead meat okay it's hard if you study
Buddhism for a long time it's hard to
have sexual attraction to someone
because you know you just look at them
and you're like oh green that's why
people drink wine I think they can
they can they can forget who's really
there okay all right little guy koala
chopping by the way I mean higher school
you can be attractive forever
okay higher school that's a goal you can
be beautiful forever and you don't have
to run okay higher school plant the
seeds have a super sexy body okay
forever and that's fine okay that's
wonderful
okay maybe it's because we feel the
possibility of that we are attracted to
be
now maybe it's because we feel the
possibility that they could be angels
you see maybe that's why we're attracted
physically to people because the main
shape you will retain you will still
have the same you still have two arms
you still have two legs okay you still
have a head so higher school you should
be planning to make an immortal body I'd
like to call it living diamond super
sexy okay super attractive okay what GQ
Buddha GQ GQ store on
I don't ask jumping okay Luke gag palaca
pinion number Tori douchey if you're
attracted to the way the person moves
you know when she walks down the street
she's like that and the guy is like you
know if the get-get-get means the beauty
of movement okay then then you do the
number tour walk then you put their leg
over there and their arm over there and
because the sooner or later it's gonna
be like that your your arms are gonna
get divorced from your feet your heads
gonna get divorced from your shoulders
you know don't be so attracted to how
they move their arms and legs there
those arms and legs are going to be
separated got it
they're gonna divorce the body okay
number eight solid sapa roopinder
chopping in blue congee Boucher there
are parts of the body which are bone and
the most famous attractive one is the
teeth okay oh she has such beautiful
white teeth you know and so T's or other
you know pretty called shape of the
bones you know like a ballet dancers
yeah something you know in some
countries when they choose children for
the Olympics or for ballet they measure
the bones to see if they're all the
proportion what Andres talked about
yesterday if you can measure all the
bones and predict if a person is going
to go up to be more attractive or more
strong even as a child so if you're if
you have some attraction to the bone
part of your body then what what
meditation skeleton yeah including I
think skull is the most powerful one but
skeleton meditation see them as a
skeleton okay these beautiful white
teeth of this sexy model are gonna be in
a skull rolling around in the ground
okay got it
number nine last one okay Carlton yep
Nicola opinion but number super douchey
so in India in ancient times it was
traditional to burn bodies right to burn
the body and so if you're particularly
attracted to both the complexion and
general shape of this person then try to
fast forward to the cremation and see
them burning see the body burning okay
this beautiful color skin this nice
white skin or this beautiful ebony skin
and this beautiful shape is just imagine
it burning during the funeral cool when
they cremated Ken Rinpoche I was on a
flight I wasn't there I was in India but
they say the skull fell out of the stupa
and rolled towards the people and
everybody freaked out you know here's
our Lama last week his skull is rolling
toward
in a freak out you know so it's like
that okay we're all gonna be burning
okay so okay are you depressed yeah good
so those are meditations you can try if
you're having trouble especially with
attraction to someone else's partner
okay or even your own partner if you're
attached to it in an unhealthy way and
you can try those meditations they are
lower school which the Deaf and my
definition of lower school is sometimes
it works sometimes it doesn't work
that's lower school for me
highest school always works okay high
schools always works you might as well
just plant the seeds for a living
diamond body and not have to do these
stupid meditations it's more efficient
okay got it okay alright but by the way
mmm and this is something that people
don't talk about a teacher trainings in
an ACI teacher training it's your job to
learn the lower schools also it's your
job to learn these lower schools also
why for the same reason that Buddha
invented them in the first place which
is someone might respond to this
treatment okay
there's different vitamins right some
people who give them vitamin I have a
friend or reach sister
they gave she was sick they gave her
vitamin D it made her more sing okay it
actually did I had to take her they were
going to take her kidney out or
something so because it was too much
vitamin D so different vitamins work for
different people we all have different
bodies we all have different minds we
all have different souls so learn all
the schools because you're gonna meet
somebody who's your student who needs
this meditation okay they're like Oh
teacher Daniel
I'm so attracted to this other lady's
husband I don't know what to do
you're like let me teach you the
disgusting meditation and nine-part you
do it every day
okay got it some learn everything learn
all the schools cuz you might need
someone you might meet someone who needs
it okay cool
it's nice to have a big tool kit okay
it's nice to have a big tool kit I have
a friend he's a plumber he's 66 so we
kind of like each other and he's been
adding tools to his truck for 50 years
that's a truck you know like you say can
I pick my nose he's just wait I have a
tool hey you know you should be like
this plumber 66 year old plumber you got
every buda tool you got every buda tool
okay and then you might you might not
use this meditation for five years ten
years and then you meet someone and just
ah I got the tool for you I got the
thing you need okay cool so learn all of
them all right if the Buddha taught it
it's useful for somebody all right we're
on the second primary negative emotion
and by the way to remind you there's six
primary negative emotions and we're
going to be doing meditations on them
because if they're primary you must have
them every day okay
those 84,000 bad deeds in Buddhism then
somebody said Buddha I can't remember
84,000 okay I'll give you ten here's the
top ten you know and those top ten bad
deeds three in body 4 in speech three
mental the reason they're the top ten
out of 84,000 is that you do them all
day every
day okay not once not twice you do them
every half hour
okay everybody same with these top six
of the 84,000 negative emotions okay if
it's in the top six you must be doing it
every day okay
that desire he just finished you must be
doing it we must be doing it okay got it
there's 20 as I mentioned yesterday 20
secondary negative emotions he mentioned
them as if he's going to teach them and
then he didn't teach them so I had an
idea to ask lama stanley to teach his
book tomorrow okay is that enough time
to prepare if you're a freak if you
stressed okay so he's gonna teach you
the twenty from the abhidharma he
translated it already and my suggestion
Stanley's go home think about it for a
couple hours have I had that this year
have I had that one this year and then
talk about it will will embarrass you in
front of everybody okay maybe she'll
pink and give you some from her okay but
I mean don't just read the list I mean
talk about this is my experience with
this one
okay okay got it because we don't really
know if other people are having that
experience or not but we know if we are
okay that's why I'm not doing it and
you're doing it okay so we may not get
through all six before tomorrow but
you're pretty good we're gonna put your
twenty in in the middle okay all right
here we go number two of the big ones me
buck Kong Tony
which means anger anger okay here's the
definition some chant down sent Jim my
Impala you can have it towards mister
human dictionary yeah you can have it
towards people but you can also have it
towards weather towards traffic towards
your finances towards your shoes okay
you can have anger about anything we are
so flexible
about our anger okay you can get angry
about your anger yeah that happened to
me okay goodnight Nasim Kunene arsim
means angry mine like fury okay
I'm from mine Sam subbu
do you know we're two more it's the
opposite of jumbo jam yang it means
rough it means like sandpaper okay
it means like a saw okay rough like not
nice to touch okay what's guess last
nickname in the monastery every monk has
a bad name every monk has a naughty
nickname I'm teaching you my naughty
nickname tree bark because I have a
rough complexion say hey tree bark
Chingy Papa okay don't call me shiny
Papa shingi Papa means man mr. tree bark
it means if you touch my skin it's like
not very smooth okay so my nickname in
the monster seen papa the most famous
nickname in the monastery was one day me
and member Jay went and they held a
debating contest while we were eating
dinner to impress us because we're
paying for the gadget course candidates
food and at that time we didn't have any
money everybody was eating rice every
day and we made everybody a kind of
fried Momo called Shapley okay Japanese
and it's very delicious
it's like Mapo tofu and so they were
supposed to debate to show us how cool
they are because we're paying for
everything and there's a place in the
debate where you say when you quote a
book you said shut some bait you say
share some beer
the sutra says you know chefs in Beijing
Jason butcher so the guy he was thinking
about dinner and he said ship Shapley
which means fried Momo dump dump him
dump son then guess what his nickname
was for the next 20 years yeah hey
shopping man don't come heavily ok
anyway the word here is is raw ok it
means your mind gets like tree bark your
mind gets like tree bark angry okay it's
not nice to touch the opposite word by
the way in sanskrit for zero dollars
Manju yeah Manju and the one who speaks
gently is called manjushri okay
manjushri okay it means soft like velvet
like silk okay his mind manjushri is
mind is Manju very silky soft okay cool
all right
your daenam not enough nepeta Dippet
after you get number two you want to
hurt somebody you want to hurt somebody
you want to do something to them my
specialty is passive aggression this is
special kind of aggression so like I
don't know you ask somebody for a
donation and they say no and you say
that's okay I'll pay you no I won't eat
for a week it's okay
don't worry I can do it you know I'll
just get hungry for a week I'll pay the
money myself
don't worry you you have the right to
say no
I'll probably have to stay in bed suffer
you know that this is a way to attack
somebody in a sweet way it's called
passive aggressive that's my specialty
you all have your own specialty okay
took me a long time to realize that I
was doing it okay
anyway there's different ways to hurt
people and there's different ways to
attack people and sometimes it's with a
smile right okay all right
jawsaw udemy Owatonna Sam Jindo tuba
number change again how do you get that
tree bark mine ruff mine is you meet a
trigger and we're gonna study six
triggers what triggers negative emotion
okay
what sets in English we say what sets
you off you know what what gets you
angry
what push your button right in English
what pushes your button okay there's six
buttons on every human being and we're
gonna study them okay it's part of your
items it's your next item six ways to
push a person's button one is called
McGill and McGill Mikio means this
person gets in front of your face you
can see them okay and that sets you are
okay you have a person you don't like if
you're not around them everything's okay
but if they suddenly show up at a party
they got invited to by this idiot you
know and you see them it ruins the whole
night for you you don't have fun at the
party why did they invite this person
who hurt me last year I don't like so
that's called okay that's the first
trigger I'm going to teach you first
trigger for a negative emotion is the
presence of the thing you don't like or
the presence of the woman you're
attracted to that's already married you
see it I mean the presence of the object
is the first trigger
what's the antidote yeah avoid a runaway
avoid them
is it an ultimate antidote no is it an
antidote yeah then you should say
immediately must be lower school gamer
must be lower school you know try to
avoid all women okay try to avoid all
people who piss you off move to a
different City
I'll tell I predict you're gonna meet
him on a plane somewhere okay but this
is one lower school method of dealing
with your negative emotions avoid the
object and and it's a big part of vinaya
concentric circles you know if you never
leave the monastery you will never see a
woman you will never have desire okay
then Jesse lotar who you're gonna meet
this week he liked laughs when he heard
that he says you know the women come
here to deliver milk in the morning from
the cows on the village and they they
bump into a mark if you have karma
you're gonna meet them if a woman enters
the monastery once in a hundred years
you're gonna be the monk who meets them
you see that means he said this is low
definitely lower score you know you say
I'm never going to talk to you again
you're gonna be stuck next to them on a
plane it happened to me it was
interesting it wasn't my okay I I spent
the whole day marrying this couple and
they did they they had this big big
plans and I I was kind of irritated
because I said I'd stay for an hour I
had to stay for like six hours and they
made all these promises and stuff and
then they got divorced for I don't know
a year and then I'm sitting in a plane
and the lady sits down next to me and
she cries the whole flight
you know and I'm like
you know I didn't do anything I just
married you guys you know and I think if
you have a new policy of charging people
$10,000 if they get divorced before
years over because usually I do it for
free I'm thinking about it okay anyway
what I mean is the approach to your
negative emotions I've tried to avoid
the trigger of the person who sets you
off is not a very good system because
somehow they will run into you all right
okay so anyway here it says when you see
the person you hate then suddenly your
mind gets tree-bark it gets like
unpleasant okay danyoung then he says
well what's the result of anger we
talked about a lot in Taiwan right last
month we did level 10 which is called
yeah I was gonna call it how to avoid
anger or never get upset and then I
decided to call the course decide level
10 is called impossible anger and that
means in the kitchen if your husband
yells at you if you understand emptiness
it's impossible to get angry it's not
you have to control yourself
you can't get angry okay and that's the
ultimate solution to anger is understand
that the person who pisses you are comes
from you you know it's a good way to
comfort people who say they're irritated
by everybody in the group you say yeah
life is a mirror
then suddenly that real quiet
everything you see the percentage of
irritating people you mean it's a direct
result of the percentage of irritation
inside of you how irritating you are to
other people if you say 99% of the
people at Diamond Mountain are
irritating you aren't what you're really
saying is I'm 99% irritating
okay peope well-trained buddhists keep
their mouths shut
you can hate other people but don't tell
anybody okay because you're just
declaring how irritating you are because
what you see is coming from you exactly
the percentage okay if you're twenty
five percent
angry person and you walk into a room
with four people one of them is gonna be
angry okay that's just higher middle way
okay all right by the way he's teaching
a very large group mixed there are high
gashes there there are high reincarnated
llamas there and there are many farmers
there so he's having to adjust his his
message okay
he's having to mix in lower school okay
got it all right
Condor DK Panik gets a jump now when we
taught DC at level 10 we went into great
detail about a subject with shanty de la
covers very well which is that anger has
a special ability to burn your bank
account of good seeds anger has a unique
ability to burn your bank account of
good sees more than any other of the 26
negative emotions anger has this unique
power to burn up your bed
your good seats okay cool yeah
yeah I know let's say it freezes them so
you know when you do the four powers
part of the goal is to put the seeds
into suspended animation
what are you call in cyril Jenny yeah
you want to freeze them
you don't really destroy them and you're
correct what you said is correct you
kind of freeze them they never open and
the same with the negative same same
with the positive states okay you can
think of it that way you still have them
but they never open okay which is as bad
as not having them okay all right
and by the way the question you asked is
a huge subject in the module maker
literature
okay huge subject you know how is it
that it burns your good seeds and you
know are there special conditions for
example there's a huge discussion of the
karmic object you see are you talking
about Bodhisattvas are you talking about
our hearts are you talking about normal
people you know what is it that burns
your bad seeds so if you want to study
that stick around it'll probably come in
the gardener okay all right so he says
kimchi kimchi means the big problem
about anger is that it destroys your
good seeds okay
yeah yeah you could take them out of the
refrigerator yeah you could I say you
could but but there's books written
about this subject so it's a long story
all right you have an item in your book
it should be a forest fire something
like that
yeah number 21 I think sorry for ya
number four right okay so when you
meditate in the afternoons this week you
can just follow these pictures okay and
it's very effective
okay so just follow the pictures okay
this afternoon if you have free time
after your nappy-nap meditate on the
forest fire you know when your husband
yells at you okay my my philosophy tell
them you're an and you know you
shouldn't get angry and I didn't do what
you think I did and and you're a fool
and etc but I'm not gonna burn up my
debit card a good karma getting mad at
you I'm so mad at you I'm not gonna get
mad at you
I understand okay I hate you so much I'm
gonna insult you I'm not I'm just gonna
ignore you you know I'm not gonna get
angry you don't deserve to be the person
who burns up my bank account okay got it
so the best way to show your anger is to
be cool okay and it really irritates
other people who hate you you know they
want you to get upset they want you to
get angry they want to see your face all
red and you just smile and say you know
I'd love to get angry at you you deserve
it but personally I don't want to wreck
my good seeds for trudeau's tomorrow you
seen I mean like you're not worth it to
know you know okay and there's a joke in
Buddhism that if you really want to
irritate your enemy be successful and
happy
it's the most irritating thing you can
do okay don't go online and fight with
them okay just have fun and have a good
life and that's the best way to irritate
them okay I specialize in this okay we
got a little bit more to go and then
we're gonna take a break okay I taught
you this morning that's a good way to
keep your students in the class even if
you don't intend to stop soon
but I do okay so predict oh-seok doing
cone to chain when people kill each
other when people punch each other when
people attack each other online it's all
due to number two
bad bad emotion number two anger okay
all this war you know destroys cities
III so I live in the desert I live in on
a mountain I live on a dirt road I live
in the smallest legal house you can own
in Arizona and so I I spend a lot of
time planting trees you know I want
trees and it's hard it's like getting
honorable it's like teaching long room
to people and it takes a lot of patience
and it takes many years watering you
know taking care of it keeping the deer
away from it and then I go on TV and I
our internet and I watch up somebody
bombing or some country and I see all
the trees go down and I you know the
people's bad but the trees is worse you
know I'm like do you know how long it
took to make that tree you know do you
know how hard people work to grow that
tree and you just destroyed a hundred of
them with your little bomb you know so
anger is extremely destructive it
destroys many many years of of work to
build cities
to plant trees to to raise children to
have children and raise them and then
send them and kill them it's
tremendously destructive and it's just a
thought it's just a it's just a movement
of the mind right the simple it's just
thoughts that blow up countries and and
kill tens of thousands of people and
every person that died their mom worked
so hard on them like a tree you know
they were so hard to to give birth to
this child and they worked so hard to
feed them and the father worked for the
money and and then you just send them
off to fight in some stupid war that
doesn't mean anything and kill all this
I gave a talk at a military academy in
America and they're all these like young
20 year old you know I'm gonna be top
gun fighter pilot you know I'm like yeah
okay then they come home with no leg and
boy they they don't believe this top gun
stuff you know it's not romantic anymore
don't believe all these gentle on our
movies Jen lungs son Jen lungs there's a
famous Rambo movies in in China they
borrowed it from America you guys
stopped borrowing bad stuff America try
to find something good I don't know like
McDonald's don't take all this poison
stuff okay those violent movies forget
it okay
it's not romantic Top Gun is not
romantic okay
people lose their legs they come home
with no leg their whole life they are
messed up their alcoholic did you know
some okay war is not romantic okay
shooting people in movies is not noble
okay and it all comes from from two
seconds of the mind moving you see all
war all that came from that okay so
right there you wanna be a hero
you know military hero fight this one
okay then you don't destroy trees and
kids and got it okay
anyway if you can't control your anger
it will destroy countries and hundreds
of thousands of people okay all right
tanks on I'm almost done okay I can see
that I can see it I'll do two more lines
I promise
one is for number one and the one is for
number two okay
tanks on car chicken yankee llama took
tomb sarah turbo controller many
important agenda meaty young then there
was a custom in tibet in the monasteries
especially that if you had a lama who
got angry a lot because in buddhism
you're not supposed to say anything bad
about your llama especially a taunting
llama there came to be a secondary
language for example if your llama was a
really tight fisted cheap never share
money it became a tradition to call them
rule apple which means thrifty my llama
never wastes money it means my llama
won't give you a penny but you're not
supposed to say you know so there became
in Tibet there came this language
sometimes you can call it Twilight
language but it's a language to refer to
your llamas false in a polite way
okay so here he gives an example my
llama is tucked um my holy llama is hard
sometimes heats up okay what's it mean
he gets angry a lot he hits his students
a lot my holy llamas heart heats up
sometimes you know and it means he gets
angry okay she gets angry she
she hits us I had it okay not very often
but some my llama had holy hard heat
sometimes maybe Gatien motor we'll talk
about it anyway
he says listen and and he was a very
honest man pop unka and he said things
that other people wouldn't say and he
would look those high Lamas in the we're
talking reincarnated Lamas you know and
he'd look him in the eye and say look
don't get pissed off of your students
I'm not gonna say holy heart is hot
let's let's say the real thing you know
you are a bad example you're a high
incarnated llama and you're a bad
example and he would say it and he got a
lot of trouble this way okay
anyway you can give it a polite name but
then he quotes a famous book okay ready
and then we'll take a pee-pee just one
little quotation stands between you and
the bathroom say shade on double dick
permit supper double car to me okay so
we got to go to the car tube which in
Sanskrit is tapas okay tapas and tapas
came into the word tepid it means heat
spiritual heat it means tough practice
tough guy practice okay tough guy
practice real gentle on Rambo tough guy
practice
okay who's tough guy you know like tough
guy can I don't know there's a llama in
Sarah one of my llamas who stopped a
train he just the Train tried to move
and he tried to move and he moved and
the train didn't move okay
and then everybody said oh my god he's a
tough guy he's a tough guy you know or
these guys
I don't know stand out in the Sun all
day you know meditate in the snow okay
meditate in the snow for two days
something like that then everyone is
like wow top us you know spiritual
warrior and everybody's like wow stop
the train
you know wow sadness no for two days
meditated didn't open his eyes this is a
real you know and Shanti Devi says bull
that's not a lot that's not a tough
guy oh ok Shanti Devi
what's a tough guy a tough guy is the
woman who comes home from work opens the
kitchen door the husband screams and
she's chill that's a warrior that's a
spiritual world
don't tell me about people sitting in
the snow okay don't tell me about the
Lama who stop the train that's not
difficult compared to staying cool when
someone's yelling at you it's much more
difficult than stopping a train or
sitting in the snow for two days then
staying cool in the kitchen when your
husband goes crazy okay you want a
spiritual warrior
it's those women in the kitchen who used
emptiness who take refuge in emptiness
and don't yell back that's warrior those
people deserve you know in America to
give you this war medal probably in
China they have what I don't know but
that's the people who deserve a medal
not these people go out and shoot
somebody with a gun that doesn't take
courage it takes courage to stand in the
kitchen and not get angry that's courage
okay got it it's very beautiful you want
a spiritual warrior it's the woman who
doesn't yell and her husband because she
wants to stop the yelling okay she stops
the war the people who stop war are more
brave than the people who fight worse
got it and the people who stop wars in
their own mind are more brave than the
people who stop wars on the ground
got it that's courage that's war courage
that's a war hero
okay got it because why first line
I thought with dick but main if you rate
bad karma you know what's number one
anger of all the bad comments anger why
it destroys all the good things it's
number one on top of dick by me
means there is no bad angers number one
on the bad karma list that's the first
line second line says patience is number
one on the war he wrote this the person
who can keep their patience is that it's
a real war hero okay
much more difficult than shooting people
with a gun or dropping bombs on people
okay that's not so hard you just push
the thing right you stand there and push
the thing but to keep cool in the
kitchen if your husband's going on for
an hour or a day or a month that's a war
hero okay that's a warrior okay so if
you can do it you should feel proud of
you know if you can stay cool in the
kitchen the people yelling at your
people criticizing your online and
you're like yeah I'm not gonna wreck my
good things for you you know I'm gonna
stay cool
okay I'm not gonna answer you okay cool
man
all right take a break be a warrior
we only have half an hour and I was
thinking what would be fun to do and
it's depressing to talk about anger so
long so we're support we have another
job this week which I mentioned earlier
today we are reviewing the past eight
years we are reviewing the past eight
years and we're doing it with pictures
okay
it's to make it easier and these are
other meditations you can do in the
afternoon if you feel like it okay if
you don't have enough work you can do it
in the afternoon but especially those of
you who would like to be an ACI teacher
who teaches meditation or lamrim if you
want to be if your master degree you
want to teach Lamia or meditation then
these are for you
okay here we go I'm supposed to be doing
them faster but I talk too much
so these are actually left over from
Thailand or something okay I'm sorry
sorry Jasmine we're too busy in Thailand
swimming and okay just kidding
so Tim I'm on 78 which is a young lady
working on a computer and yeah okay
those and what we're doing is review
we're reviewing the whole big long room
in pictures and the examination for this
master's degree is mainly we show you
the picture and you tell me the story
okay with so I'll show you the picture
without the writing and you tell me what
the picture is about so I'm gonna be
checking starting tomorrow I'll show
pictures and then someone's gonna tell
me what it's about okay so you're trying
to memorize the picture and what it
means okay you're ready Tim I don't know
okay
I'll stall some more and the pictures
are square
and they also have colors on them Tim's
gonna print them out maybe by tomorrow
by the way venerable Jigme had some fun
that maybe you want to do she was trying
to find the page number in the
translation that connect to the picture
so I'm working with the Tibetan I'm
going through the Tibetan but if you
want to have fun like with the Chinese
translation you can you can say this
picture is on this page of the book okay
okay here we go
in the beginning of the lamb rim before
he starts to learn him he sells the
Lamia okay and as a teacher as a a CI
teacher your first job is to sell a CI
courses okay before you start teaching
the course you have to tell them how
cool it's gonna be if they learn the
course okay got it
so it's traditional in Buddhism to sell
the teaching before you give it it's
like when you sell a car it's exactly
like selling a car and that the couple
comes in you grab them and you say do
you realize how great the stereo is on
this car like there's no stereo like
this on any car in the whole world and
these tires they're round and black and
okay like you have to talk about the
cool stuff okay it's a tradition we're
on this part we're on this part we
didn't get an alarm in okay so item 78
by the way if we just started the alarm
room why are we already on picture
number 78 I started this course
backwards I taught the end of the alarm
em first why would I do that yeah
because it's the meditation part so what
my strategy was eight years ago I
started from the end of the book and we
studied emptiness and we studied
meditation schemata and de pasión are
not
the passion oh okay and we studied the
end of the book first because we wanted
to use seeds inside the Lamia so we had
to talk about emptiness and then we
wanted to use meditation so I started
from the end of the book so what are we
gonna do when we hit the end of the book
now we're gonna jump to another book you
see so I I will not cover again the end
of this book I will cover that the same
topic from tsongkhapa's big big lemon
Tim Oh big lemon okay got it
that's my strategy that so we already
finished all the pictures that relate to
meditation and emptiness which is not
very long in this Lamia because he
didn't want to compete with the guy
who's already did it better okay its own
cup okay so here we go in m78
one of the selling points of the long
room is look you can do it okay it's big
it takes years and you can do it okay
and that's all don't resist it okay and
I'll tell you something cute about this
picture that you're gonna repeat back to
me when I give you the test later this
week
ready who's learning in this picture the
father good okay
why does the daughter have to teach the
father about the internet because he's
from the paper generation like Geshe
Michael okay it's very difficult for us
you know people say like dr. Wu's wife
we had dinner with dr. Wu and her and
she said I'll just reach out you you
know I'm like what's WeChat and she's
like you don't know it yet I'm like no
she took my phone she she put WeChat on
I said wait wait wait wait I I don't
know I don't know where each other I
don't know if I wanted she's I got shut
up
you know she's like put which now you
got WeChat you know I'm reach out you
just know okay so we resisted you know
my generation you say WeChat we're like
I'll do it tomorrow it's okay I'll do it
tomorrow you know cuz it's uncomfortable
for us you know I don't know what's we
chat
I have Scott you know I have Scott which
what button do I push to send an email
he's like push this button and that's
that's really why I keep him around okay
he teaches me how to use all these
things you know he's not afraid of them
okay Scott has this beautiful quality
he's not afraid of new tech he just
attacks it he learns it he calls the
company and says you messed up this
button doesn't work they're like I'm
sorry and okay he has bravery courage
about Newton okay and we tend to I tend
to be afraid I'm kind of afraid of it I
don't want to learn it you know because
actually I'm afraid of it I also think
if I wait three years it'll be obsolete
and I don't have to learn it so anyway
don't have that attitude about this mom
room don't think look I'm not a guest
I'm not a monk I'm not a nun I can't you
know I have a job I'm busy I can't learn
a thousand-page text and meditate on it
and you know it's you resist it and and
what this picture means is don't be well
do be like the father the father was
humble and the father went to the
daughter and said look I don't
understand this Facebook thing can you
explain it to me or what's a new one
yeah Instagram I'm like it sounds like a
kind of coffee or something did you did
you do your Instagram again I said yeah
okay so there's two choices you have you
know you can say you can resist you can
say I'm too old or I don't have time or
I have a job I can't become a lahrman
master or you can say god dammit I'm
gonna do it you know and get someone to
help you and be humble you know go to
your daughter and say look I don't get
this Instagram thing can you explain it
to me and she'll explain it to you once
and then she'll have to do it three
times okay but you got to be humble to
be successful okay admit to your
daughter you know look I don't
understand this Instagram thing and the
point of the picture is you can do it
you can do it just ask and just try and
you can do it don't avoid hard things
okay tsongkhapa's approach his whole
life was and what makes him different
from other Hamas's he attacks the hard
things and in his books he'll say this
is too easy for me to talk about you
figure it out and like words text is
called difficult points in the mind only
and we were so foolish
I said hate word let's translate this
one it's just a mind only bunk he's like
yeah I guess let's do it you know we
couldn't understand two sentences it
really is hard points you know and he
loves them and if you don't avoid hard
things in your life
you will become a master okay like go
for the hard things go for the hard
thing some emotional things too you know
if there's a problem with your partner
some and you kind of don't want to talk
about that one attack that one go for
the hard spots then the easy spots are
easy got it all right so if you see this
picture what are you gonna tell me don't
be afraid of this new tech called lamb
rim okay don't get scared of new tech
learn new things okay most people stop
learning after high school
or after college and they get out of the
habit of learning new things and those
rare people who keep learning their
whole life like Scott it's really cool
and and their mind just gets more and
more cool okay got it
don't be afraid of the long room and
don't say it's too long if don't say you
can't do it okay
don't avoid hard things got it next
picture there's a list of reasons why
you shouldn't come to a teaching or a
teacher training or Diamond Mountain
okay or DCI class or okay got it
there's a list in the lamrim of lower
motivations for coming to a teaching
okay
so I made a picture out of it okay
number one its blessing so is it wrong
to come to a teaching because you want a
blessing of being there it's not wrong
it's only wrong if that's the only thing
you want okay and this is talking about
people who say I'm gonna go to Diamond
Mountain I'm gonna go to the garden of
course I don't understand anything guess
I was talking about and I won't but it's
a blessing to be in the room okay that's
a okay but it's stupid you know don't
just go for blessing you know learn the
thing okay some people in Tibet used to
go to these big teachings just to get
the blessing and before they walked in
the room they said I cannot learn that
I'm I'm not a gishy
you know I cannot learn done and he says
don't come if that's why you came here
don't come second bad reason it's called
this a code word word to put in your
data bank to to get more money later say
young young it's a special
Tibetan word it means to go to a
teaching because your friends are going
okay to go to an initiation because your
friends are
and I often hear that are you gonna go
to color taka
yeah why my friends going you know
people just go because oh you know my
friends are going that's what the
picture means okay now you know what the
picture means when you see this picture
you're gonna say oh that's talking about
five bad reasons to go to a teaching
number one I just want to go for the
blessing I know I won't understand
number two I just want to go cuz my
friends are going okay number three I
just want to go to get more information
that I can teach in my own classes I'm
not going to learn something myself I'm
not trying to improve myself I want to
know the lower-middle way school so I
can teach it got it bad motivation never
take a teaching without applying it to
your self okay don't ever take a
teaching without applying it to yourself
okay otherwise you're wasting your time
don't collect knowledge don't collect
school systems okay it's learn all the
school systems and use them on yourself
yesterday we used to mine only school in
a very cool way I think we had a good
explanation from it from professorword
okay all right that's now power power
means I will get more high position as a
teacher if I know more things you know
people will be impressed with me okay
and I will get more power over people
you know I could be the teacher and not
the student okay
and then the last one is more like
impressing you know and you see this in
Buddhist groups okay somebody says I
don't know you're like
sitting with lunch with somebody and
they say you know it looks like your
consciousness number seven didn't
understand your conscience number eight
you know and you're like I have no idea
what you're talking about
and you're like I know I know I know
mind only school let me help you okay
you it's the cocktail party you meet a
cute girl at the cocktail party do you
know about consciousness seven eight and
you don't want to help them you just
want to impress them on how much you
know okay so that's why you go to the
teaching you want more information to
use at the cocktail party to impress the
ladies at the cocktail party okay got it
these are five reasons not to go to a
teaching okay mainly it's the opposite
of the intention to apply the teaching
to your own life okay and that should be
your motivation okay your only
motivation I'm sick I'm going to get
treatment at Diamond Mountain okay in
Buddhism it's called the member duchesne
this man is SEMA
yeah yeah the whole thing is a medical
treatment the retreated Diamond Mountain
is a medical treatment where are you
going next week I'm going to America
where don't mom what for medical mental
medical treatments okay yeah that's the
attitude I need it I need treatment you
know I've got these diseases called
anger desire okay and I'm going for
treatment okay cool that's the right
motivation okay and if I treat myself
I'll be able to treat other people okay
that's okay that's a healthy motivation
okay all right next one next one yeah
okay so if you met Einstein on a plane
and you were trying to explain to him
the theory of relativity or quantum
physics okay you didn't recognize him
and you're he's on the plane you're on
the plane do you know anything you want
to hear me explain quantum physics to
you and he's like well and before he can
say no you start explaining quantum
physics to him and I have this happen to
me pretty frequently I don't know some
of us start explaining my jamika to me
you know and I'm like it's all wrong
everything's wrong and I'm like it
happens in China sometimes people start
explaining diamond cutter souter to me
it happened recently right and I'm I
just polite I I go okay and you don't
say I spent 25 years on that you know
you know yeah okay and the point is as I
said yesterday the long rim comes from a
person who knows in english we have this
idiom oh he thinks he's mr. know-it-all
he thinks he's mr. know-it-all but the
Buddha really is
mr. Noah okay he sees everything in all
times including what you're thinking
okay to him looking at your nose and
looking at your inner thoughts it's the
same this the same so he wrote the
sutras for you personally okay don't
don't doubt it
okay he he wrote he gave this teaching
two and a half thousand years ago for
the people at Diamond Mountain in 2019
April okay
don't doubt it don't think he doesn't
have this capacity if you think he
doesn't have that capacity you're
wasting your time here because you're
trying to get the capacity you see the
reason to be here is to become a Buddha
so you can write teachings for people
who come 2,000 years later
okay got in you're talking about a
doctor who sees the future of your
disease you know like they say you need
radiation treatment and this and you say
why and they say it's gonna fix you in
six months three days in two hours
because I can see it okay so when they
give you a teaching it's just for you
and it's exactly what you need which
means why waste your time with other
kinds of teachings personally I mean it
seems crazy to me if it's possible to
get a teaching from a person who read
your mind two and a half thousand years
ago and knew everything about your life
and knows your future they know when
you're gonna become Buddha they are
already communicating with you as a
beauty Buddha in the future I used to
sit in the toilet at work when I was
having a bad day and I would talk to
Geshe Michael future Buddha
I'd say Jessie Michael future Buddha I'm
having a bad day he's like don't worry
you're gonna be me in a while
people say what do you talk about when
you're in the toilet don't worry about
it okay
so if you can get a TV from somebody
like that then you don't have to add
stuff okay don't worry about it I it
drives me crazy when people say oh this
Buddhism it just needs a little more
psychology you know like psychology
number 84 that's gonna be you know the
books gonna disappear in two years it's
what's in the airport this week you know
I'm like okay you know maybe an
omniscient being might know what they're
talking about you know maybe they don't
need this week's in psychology book you
okay got it it really irritates me it's
a what Marsha
pet peeve I'm gonna teach you this idiom
whether you want to or not
okay pet peeve it drives me crazy you
can say it that way I allow you to say
it that way like Peter drives me crazy
okay
people try to fix Buddhism or they add
to Buddhism you know something that was
written last year and will be disappear
next year it lasted for two and a half
thousand years that diamond cutter Sutra
is the most printed book in history it's
the first book ever printed in history
okay it's got more copies out than the
Bible okay you can it's probably okay
you probably don't need to fix it Donna
it wouldn't have survived if it wasn't
useful okay if the diamond cutter suitor
didn't help anybody
it wouldn't be around okay there must be
something in there okay okay so I said
it's foolish to try to out think an
omniscient being and it's also foolish
to follow something that was not written
by an omniscient being why waste your
time with someone's new psychology
that's gonna be out of date next year
why waste your time you can you know I
know you guys you're 30 you're 40 or
you're 14 I don't know but uh I can tell
you you don't have time to read all the
crap that's available you don't have
time and you don't have time to look at
cats on YouTube jumping up and down you
know someone sent me this video guess
not you got to see this video I'm like
okay and it's cats jumping up and down
when they get frightened and I'm like
why you send me this video about cats
jumping up and down I don't have time
I'm dying I have I have this many years
I know it I know how many minutes I have
I don't have time for this year's
psychology okay and and as you get older
you will appreciate me telling you that
don't waste your time go to the big
stuff and don't be resist the tech the
hi-tech okay jump into it
guess that's too hard this upper middle
way stuff is too hard I don't care
attack it learn into the instant grim
just kidding I know the name I don't
know how to use it okay so just don't
resist it use it okay okay don't really
from 66 I'm telling all you 30s and 20s
and other ones don't waste a minute of
your life on that stuff you don't have
time if you work very hard you might
make it but if you waste your time on
these cats jumping on YouTube definitely
you won't make it you don't have time
okay you just don't have time okay so I
said we can't watch movies I didn't say
that
it's a Buddhist responsibility to learn
how to relax it's a Buddhist
responsibility to go see gentle on our
and watch him shoot up Africa okay and
we did right we went and it was fun and
the next day we were better students we
had
okay so I didn't say you can't watch
cats jumping you can watch cats jumping
if you're so exhausted you can't do
anything else okay if you need a break I
advise you cats jumping on YouTube okay
but but don't spend the day watching you
okay you must take your rest
you must it's a better Buddhist you're a
better Buddhist if you take rest okay me
and V went to a movie
we served her mother oh my gosh that was
a rough two days it started with washing
every dish in her house which was in
this thing okay I shouldn't say that
don't tell her
but after two days of serving you know
we were like okay you want to go buy her
some more groceries and we looked at
each other we said let's go to a movie
and let's not take mom and I'm like yeah
and okay sometimes you you gotta take a
break from your virtuous activity okay
and you will be more virtuous otherwise
you'll get grumpy and you won't make a
lot of bad C's okay so it's a Buddhist
skill to learn how to go watch a movie
and goof off sometimes we go for dinner
and boy we eat okay
no green drinks at that dinner yeah
sometimes I just they come out with a
big tray of dessert you know I said
bring the tray before dinner and they're
like which one do you want I said why do
you think I want one did you ever have
anyone order all of them they're like
well once I said well now it's twice
learn how to have fun okay but don't
waste your time okay if you can work
work if you can't work take a break okay
got it
I'm not against cats
I'm just saying don't do it all the time
okay all right we finished a tea
we're out of time we're gonna start with
anyone tomorrow okay Tim do you have any
announcements or anything oh let's do a
mandala first Luca you in the mood
well it's like sushi but it's sushi okay
okay blinky and egg and party son
caching to make a scene
and I'm good
come on take a walk sorry she thought so
she sir nomination
number Cornie top so cool thank you for
coming thank you for working so hard
thank you for asking me to teach we're
gonna cover more of these tomorrow and
you'll get probably tomorrow you will
get the the reading with all of them
okay this is the review of the last
eight years of lumber okay in case you
want to take a master's degree in that
okay